# region array de nivel de dificultad
# levels = ['Beginner', 'Intermediate',  'Advanced']
"""lista de nivel de dificultad, esta lista se cargan los niveles del quiz"""
levels = ['Principiante', 'Intermedio',  'Avanzado']
# endregion array de nivel de dificultad

# region array de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel principiante
"""lista de preguntas y respuestas para el nivel principiante"""
questions_beginner = [
    # Pregunta 1
    {"question": "Please stand behind the yellow line", "options": [
        "In a Hardware store", "In a Bakery", "In a station plataform"], "answer": "In a station plataform"},
    # Pregunta 2
    {"question": "There will be one interval of sisteen minutes", "options": [
        "In a theater", "In a hall", "In a Field"], "answer": "In a theater"},
    # Pregunta 3
    {"question": "Get 2 tent pay 1", "options": [
        "In a museum", "In a camping site", "In a room"], "answer": "In a camping site"},
    # Pregunta 4
    {"question": "Please leave your room by 11 AM", "options": [
        "In a Inn", "In a Cottage", "In a room"], "answer": "In a Inn"},
    # Pregunta 5
    {"question": "Do not swim alone", "options": [
        "At a beach", "In the shower", "In a theater"], "answer": "At a beach"},
    # Pregunta 6
    {"question": "Bed and breafast", "options": [
        "In a swiming pool", "In an Inn", "In a Field"], "answer": "In an Inn"},
    # Pregunta 7
    {"question": "Children playing", "options": [
        "Toy  store", "In a playground", "In a art gallery"], "answer": "In a playground"},
    # Pregunta 8
    {"question": "Special meat and chicken", "options": [
        "In a bakery", "In a restaurant", "In a butchery"], "answer": "In a butchery"},
    # Pregunta 9
    {"question": "Loading/Unloading zone",
        "options": ["On a sidewalk", "In a path"], "answer": "On a sidewalk"},
    # Pregunta 10
    {"question": "Baby changing area in a restrooms", "options": [
        "Falso", "Verdadero"], "answer": "Verdadero"},
    # Pregunta 11
    {"question": "Cotton and silk 50% off?", "options": [
        "On a box", "On a brand", "On a label"], "answer": "On a label"},
    # Pregunta 12
    {"question": "Boats leave at 8:30 pm", "options": [
        "In a quay", "In a cliff", "In a woods"], "answer": "In a quay"},
    # Pregunta 13
    {"question": "Anyone caught hunting will face a fine of 100", "options": [
        "In a river", "In a natural park", "On a road"], "answer": "In a natural park"},
    # Pregunta 14
    {"question": "You take your car here to fill it up with oil", "options": [
        "Petrol station", "Ball", "Bike"], "answer": "Petrol station"},
    # Pregunta 15
    {"question": "This in an adhesive substance used for sticking objects together", "options": [
        "Court", "Magazine ", "Glue"], "answer": "Glue"},
    # Pregunta 16
    {"question": "Boats leave at 8:30 pm", "options": [
        "In a quay", "In a cliff ", "In a woods"], "answer": "In a quay"},
    # Pregunta 17
    {"question": "Anyone caught hunting will face a fine of 100", "options": [
        "In a river", "On a road ", "In a natural park"], "answer": "In a natural park"},
    # Pregunta 18
    {"question": "Parcel pick up fine $150", "options": [
        "In a railway", "In an airport terminal ", "In a playground"], "answer": "In an airport terminal"},
    # Pregunta 19
    {"question": "It's used to make calls", "options": [
        "Phone", "Flight ", "Calls"], "answer": "Phone"},
    # Pregunta 20
    {"question": "This is what you call your sister's son", "options": [
        "Uncle", "Aunt ", "Nephew"], "answer": "Nephew"},
    # Pregunta 21
    {"question": "This is how you feel when you win a game", "options": [
        "Blushimg", "Hungry ", "Happy"], "answer": "Happy"},
    # Pregunta 22
    {"question": ".This is how you feel when you win a game", "options": [
        "Blushimg", " Hungry ", "Happy"], "answer": "Happy"},
    # Pregunta 23
    {"question": ".You put your clothes in this when you travel",
        "options": ["Suitcase", "Message ", "Pilow"], "answer": "Suitcase"},
    # Pregunta 24
    {"question": "Special things to repair cars", "options": [
        "Cast", "Tools ", "Coach"], "answer": "Tools"},
    # Pregunta 25
    {"question": "It's a common drug wich relieves pain", "options": [
        "Beach", "Wallet ", "Aspirin"], "answer": "Aspirin"},
    # Pregunta 26
    {"question": "This is a device for making juice", "options": [
        "Mouse", "Blender ", "Tray"], "answer": "Blender"},
    # Pregunta 27
    {"question": "These are for your feet", "options": [
        "Pot", "Socks ", "Envelope"], "answer": "Socks"},
    # Pregunta 28
    {"question": "A portable rectangular travelling case for carrying money", "options": [
        "Glue", "Flask ", "Wallet"], "answer": "Wallet"},
    # Pregunta 29
    {"question": "This container is used to keep cold or hot drinks", "options": [
        "Lamp", "Flask ", "Bored"], "answer": "Flask"},
    # Pregunta 30
    {"question": "You fry egs and omelets in this", "options": [
        "Pan", "Waiter ", "Fridge"], "answer": "Pan"}
]
# endregion array de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel principiante

# region array de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel medio
"""lista de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel medio"""
questions_intermediate = [
    # Pregunta 1
    {"question": "I'm not feeling so well?", "options": [
        "That's great", "What's wrong", "Where is the doctor?"], "answer": " What's wrong"},
    # Pregunta 2
    {"question": "I can't find my glasses.Have you seen them?", "options": [
        "Here they are", "Me too", "Oh that's great"], "answer": "Here they are"},
    # Pregunta 3
    {"question": "I'm not fan of football?", "options": [
        "I don't like him", "I am not either ", "I don't play football"], "answer": "I am not either"},
    # Pregunta 4
    {"question": "So, how was your weekend?", "options": [
        "It was ok", "I don't like it ", "She was at the beach"], "answer": "It was ok"},
    # Pregunta 5
    {"question": "So, how was your weekend?", "options": [
        "It was ok", "I don't like it ", "She was at the beach"], "answer": "It was ok"},
    # Pregunta 6
    {"question": "How are your parents?", "options": [
        "They're great.Thanks for asking", "I don't know where they are", "My parents are at home"], "answer": "They're great.Thanks for asking"},
    # Pregunta 7
    {"question": "Who's the new kid in school?", "options": [
        "He is ok", "I think his name is Josh", "He is school"], "answer": "I think his name is Josh"},
    # Pregunta 8
    {"question": "Where is the cafeteria?", "options": [
        "It's next to the cafeteria", "The food is good", "It's near the library"], "answer": "It's near the library"},
    # Pregunta 9
    {"question": "My cellphone ran out of battery?", "options": [
        "Can you lend me your charger?", "You can lend me your charger", "You can borrow my carger"], "answer": "You can borrow my carger"},
    # Pregunta 10
    {"question": "I hate shopping", "options": [
        "So do i", "Certainly ", "That's al right"], "answer": "So do i"},
    # Pregunta 11
    {"question": "Do you want milk for your coffe", "options": [
        "No, thanks", "I want a coffee ", "I like coffee"], "answer": "No, thanks"},
    # Pregunta 12
    {"question": "Are you ok?", "options": [
        "Yes, inside", "Yes, please ", "Yes,i am"], "answer": "Yes,i am"},
    # Pregunta 13
    {"question": "Whose seat is this?", "options": [
        "I'm not sure", "Yes,you can ", "Jenny's done it"], "answer": "I'm not sure"},
    # Pregunta 14
    {"question": "14.When will dad be home?", "options": [
        "Yesterday", "3 hours", "Soon"], "answer": "Soon"},
    # Pregunta 15
    {"question": "15.What time's lunch ?", "options": [
        "Tomorrow", "At 12 o' clock", "Two hours"], "answer": "At 12 o'clock"},
    # Pregunta 16
    {"question": "16.How long was the film?", "options": [
        "It was on yesterday", "I don't remember", "For two hours"], "answer": " For two hours"},
    # Pregunta 17
    {"question": "17.How old are you?", "options": [
        "Sixteen", "Fine,thanks", "How do you do?"], "answer": "Sixteen"},
    # pregunta 18
    {"question": "18.When's your birthday?", "options": [
        "Congratulations!", "I'm 14", "Next month"], "answer": "Next month"},
    # pregunta 19
    {"question": "19.I've got a pain?", "options": [
        "Where is it?", "Why is it?", "When is it?"], "answer": " Where is it?"},
    # pregunta 20
    {"question": "20.Look at the sky?", "options": [
        "It's going to rain", "Do you need to?", "Of course it has"], "answer": "It's going to rain"},
    # Pregunta 21
    {"question": "21.Where's Amanda gone?", "options": [
        "She's at the station", "She'll arrive tomorrow", "She's going to leave tonight"], "answer": "She's at the station"},
    # Pregunta 22
    {"question": "22.I would like pasta,please", "options": [
        "Certainly", "I hope so", "Do you like it?"], "answer": "Certainly"},
    # Pregunta 23
    {"question": "23.The room costs 55 dolars a night", "options": [
        "I don't take it", "Give me two,please", "That's a lot"], "answer": "That's a lot"},
    # pregunta 24
    {"question": "24.The room costs 55 dolars a night", "options": [
        "I don't take it", "Give me two,please", "That's a lot"], "answer": "That's a lot"}
]
# endregion array de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel medio

# region textos de nivel avanzado
texts_advanced = [
    # titulo 1
    {"title": "The Joy of Gardening",
        "text": "Gardening is a wonderful hobby that brings joy to many people.\n\nIt allows individuals to connect with nature and grow their own plants.\nGardening can also be a great way to relieve _____ (1) and enjoy fresh air.\nMany gardeners love to cultivate flowers, fruits, and vegetables.\nNot only does gardening provide beautiful scenery, but it also encourages a healthy _____ (2).\nSpending time in the garden can improve mood and promote physical _____ (3).\nWhether you have a small balcony or a large yard, gardening can be a fulfilling _____ (4) for anyone."},
    # titulo 2
    {"title": "The Joy of Gardening",
        "text": "Exercise is essential for maintaining good health and well-being. Regular physical activity helps improve _____ (1) and strengthens the heart.\nIt is also effective in managing weight and reducing the risk of _____ (2).\nMany people enjoy different types of exercise, such as running, swimming, or yoga.\nEngaging in these activities can boost _____ (3) and increase energy levels.\n Additionally, exercise is known to enhance mental clarity and reduce feelings of _____ (4). Incorporating exercise into your daily routine can lead to a happier, healthier life."},
    # titulo 3
    {"title": "The Excitement of Football",
        "text": "Football is one of the most popular sports in the world. It brings people together and creates a sense of _____ (1). Watching a football match can be thrilling, especially when the score is close.\nPlayers train hard to improve their _____ (2) and teamwork. A successful team relies on strong communication and strategy to win games. Fans often show their support by wearing team _____ (3) and cheering from the stands.\nMoreover, football promotes physical fitness and encourages _____ (4) among players. Whether playing casually or competitively, football is a fantastic way to enjoy the game."},
    # titulo 4
    {"title": "The Importance of Nutrition",
        "text": "Nutrition plays a vital role in our overall health and well-being. A balanced diet provides essential _____ (1) that our bodies need to function properly. Consuming a variety of foods, including fruits, vegetables, and whole grains, is crucial for maintaining a healthy _____ (2).\nMany people struggle with making nutritious choices, often opting for processed foods high in _____ (3). These foods can lead to health issues like obesity and diabetes.\nTo improve nutrition, it is important to read food _____ (4) and understand what we are consuming. Making informed choices can lead to a healthier lifestyle and better long-term health."},
    # titulo  5
    {"title": "The Magic of Movies",
        "text": "Movies have a unique ability to transport us to different worlds. They tell stories that evoke a range of _____ (1), from laughter to tears. Watching films can be a great way to spend time with _____ (2) and escape from daily life.There are many genres of movies, including action, comedy, and drama. Each genre offers something different, catering to various _____ (3) and preferences.Filmmaking is an art that requires creativity and teamwork. Directors, writers, and actors work together to bring a story to life on the big _____ (4).Whether you prefer watching at home or in a theater, movies provide entertainment and spark our imagination."},
    # titulo  6
    {"title": "The Joy of Travel", "text": "Traveling is a wonderful way to explore new cultures and experience different _____ (1). Whether visiting historical landmarks or enjoying natural landscapes, each trip offers unique opportunities for _____ (2).Many people enjoy planning their journeys, researching destinations, and creating _____ (3) of places to visit. Traveling can also broaden our perspectives and help us understand the world better.While traveling, it’s important to embrace local customs and try new _____ (4). This can lead to unforgettable memories and connections with people from diverse backgrounds.No matter the destination, travel enriches our lives in countless ways."},
    # titulo  7
    {"title": "The Impact of Technology",
        "text": "Technology has transformed our lives in countless ways. From smartphones to artificial intelligence, it shapes how we communicate, work, and _____ (1). Many people rely on technology for daily tasks, making life more _____ (2).In education, technology has opened up new opportunities for learning. Online courses and digital resources provide access to _____ (3) information. This allows students to study at their own pace and explore various subjects.However, the rapid advancement of technology also raises _____ (4) about privacy and security. It’s essential to use technology responsibly and be aware of potential risks.Overall, technology continues to evolve, influencing our future in profound ways."},
    # titulo  8
    {"title": "The World of Programming",
        "text": "Programming is a critical skill in today’s digital age. It involves writing code to create software, applications, and websites. As technology continues to advance, the demand for _____ (1) professionals is rapidly increasing.Learning to program can enhance problem-solving _____ (2) and logical thinking. Many programming languages, such as Python, Java, and JavaScript, offer different features and are used for various _____ (3).In addition to technical skills, teamwork is essential in software development. Developers often collaborate in _____ (4) to build projects efficiently and meet deadlines.As the world becomes more reliant on technology, programming skills will remain valuable and in high demand."}

]
# endregion textos de nivel avanzado

# region array de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel avansado
"""lista de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel avansado"""
questions_advanced = [
    # Pregunta 1
    {"title": "0", "question": "Gardening can also be a great way to relieve ______", "options": [
        "boredom", "stress", "fatigue", "hunger"], "answer": "stress"},
    # Pregunta 2
    {"title": "0", "question": "It also encourages a healthy ______", "options": [
        "lifestyle", "hobby", "diet", "routine"], "answer": "lifestyle"},
    # Pregunta 3
    {"title": "0", "question": "Gardening can improve mood and promote physical ______", "options": [
        "activity", "exhaustion", "injury", "tiredness"], "answer": "activity"},
    # Pregunta 4
    {"title": "0", "question": "Gardening can be a fulfilling ______", "options": [
        "job", "task", "activity", "chore"], "answer": "activity"},
    # Pregunta 5
    {"title": "1", "question": "for anyone. Regular physical activity helps improve ______", "options": [
        "flexibility", "mood", "strength", "endurance"], "answer": "strength"},
    # Pregunta 6
    {"title": "1", "question": "It reduces the risk of ______", "options": [
        "injuries", "illness", "fatigue", "stress"], "answer": "illness"},
    # Pregunta 7
    {"title": "1", "question": "Engaging in activities can boost ______", "options": [
        "sleep", "confidence", "hunger", "boredom"], "answer": "confidence"},
    # Pregunta 8
    {"title": "1", "question": "Exercise can reduce feelings of ______", "options": [
        "happiness", "stress", "excitement", "energy"], "answer": "stress"},
    # Pregunta 9
    {"title": "2", "question": "It creates a sense of ______", "options": [
        "competition", "community", "boredom", "solitude"], "answer": "community"},
    # Pregunta 10
    {"title": "2", "question": "Players train hard to improve their ______", "options": [
        "skills", "distractions", "interests", "opinions"], "answer": "skills"},
    # Pregunta 11
    {"title": "2", "question": "Fans show their support by wearing team ______", "options": [
        "colors", "food", "flags", "names"], "answer": "colors"},
    # Pregunta 12
    {"title": "2", "question": "Football promotes physical ______", "options": [
        "fitness", "injury", "fatigue", "stress"], "answer": "fitness"},
    # Pregunta 13
    {"title": "3", "question": "among players. A balanced diet provides essential ______", "options": [
        "flavors", "nutrients", "snacks", "drinks"], "answer": "nutrients"},
    # Pregunta 14
    {"title": "3", "question": "A healthy ______", "options": [
        "diet", "routine", "activity", "sleep"], "answer": "diet"},
    # Pregunta 15
    {"title": "3", "question": "is crucial for our well-being. Processed foods are often high in ______", "options": [
        "vitamins", "minerals", "proteins", "sugar"], "answer": "sugar"},
    # Pregunta 16
    {"title": "3", "question": "It is important to read food ______", "options": [
        "recipes", "labels", "prices", "advertisements"], "answer": "labels"},
    # Pregunta 17
    {"title": "4", "question": "Movies evoke a range of ______", "options": [
        "emotions", "sounds", "images", "colors"], "answer": "emotions"},
    # Pregunta 18
    {"title": "4", "question": "Watching films can be a great way to spend time with ______",
        "options": ["friends", "strangers", "pets", "books"], "answer": "friends"},
    # Pregunta 19
    {"title": "4", "question": "Each genre offers something different, catering to various ______",
        "options": ["tastes", "sizes", "locations", "colors"], "answer": "tastes"},
    # Pregunta 20
    {"title": "4", "question": "Directors, writers, and actors work together to bring a story to life on the big ______",
        "options": ["screen", "stage", "page", "set"], "answer": "screen"},
    # Pregunta 21
    {"title": "5", "question": "Traveling allows us to experience different ______",
        "options": ["foods", "cultures", "hotels", "activities"], "answer": "cultures"},
    # Pregunta 22
    {"title": "5", "question": "Each trip offers unique opportunities for ______", "options": [
        "relaxation", "adventure", "shopping", "sleeping"], "answer": "adventure"},
    # Pregunta 23
    {"title": "5", "question": "Many people create ______", "options": ["lists", "memories", "photos", "dreams"],
     "answer": "lists"},
    # Pregunta 24
    {"title": "5", "question": "of places to visit. It’s important to try new ______",
        "options": ["activities", "customs", "friends", "routes"], "answer": "customs"},
    # Pregunta 25
    {"title": "6", "question": "Technology shapes how we communicate, work, and ______",
        "options": ["play", "sleep", "travel", "eat"], "answer": "play"},
    # Pregunta 26
    {"title": "6", "question": "Making life more ______", "options": [
        "complex", "difficult", "convenient", "boring"], "answer": "convenient"},
    # Pregunta 27
    {"title": "6", "question": "Online courses provide access to ______", "options": [
        "limited", "outdated", "valuable", "irrelevant"], "answer": "valuable"},
    # Pregunta 28
    {"title": "6", "question": "The rapid advancement of technology raises ______", "options": [
        "questions", "excitement", "ideas", "opportunities"], "answer": "questions"},
    # Pregunta 29
    {"title": "7", "question": "The demand for ______", "options": [
        "artistic", "programming", "medical", "athletic"], "answer": "programming"},
    # Pregunta 30
    {"title": "7", "question": "Learning to program can enhance problem-solving ______",
        "options": ["skills", "hobbies", "interests", "languages"], "answer": "skills"},
    # Pregunta 31
    {"title": "7", "question": "Different programming languages are used for various ______",
        "options": ["purposes", "sizes", "colors", "speeds"], "answer": "purposes"},
    # Pregunta 32
    {"title": "7", "question": "Developers often collaborate in ______", "options": [
        "isolation", "teams", "silence", "sections"], "answer": "teams"}

]
# endregion array de Preguntas y respuestas del nivel avansado

# region array de Preguntas y respuestas
"""lista de Preguntas y respuestas por defecto, esto se usa para evitar un posible error en la ejecucion de la aplicacion"""
questions = [
    # Pregunta 1
    {"question": "Please stand behind the yellow line?", "options": [
        " In a Hardware store", " In a Bakery", " In a station plataform"], "answer": " In a station plataform"}
]

# endregion array de Preguntas y respuestas

# region array de texto de preguntas nivel avanzado


def add_lectura():

    # Extraer solo las preguntas
    # lectura = [item["question"] for item in questions_advanced]
    lectura = ""

    # Recorrer la lista
    for index, question in enumerate(questions_advanced):
        print(f"Pregunta {index + 1}: {question['question']}")
        lectura += question['question']
        # print("Opciones:")
    for option in question['options']:
        # print(f"  - {option}")
        # print(f"Respuesta correcta: {question['answer']}\n")

        # print("text ", lectura)

        # Mostrar el resultado
        return lectura

# endregion array detexto de preguntas nivel avanzado
